<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-06-24T19:03:31+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Rough Notes</title><author><name>Javier Cancela</name><email>javier.cancela@hey.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">LLM concepts I - Tokenizers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/llm-concepts-i-tokenizers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LLM concepts I - Tokenizers" /><published>2024-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/llm-concepts-i-tokenizers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/llm-concepts-i-tokenizers/"><![CDATA[To understand how LLMs work, you have to understand embeddings. And to understand embeddings, you have to understand tokenizers.

LLMs receive text as input and generate text as output, but as neural networks, they work with numbers, so they first need to convert the text to numbers and then convert the resulting numbers from their calculations into words again.

Converting from text (or other types of data like audio or images) to numbers is called embedding, and we'll discuss it in a future post. For now, it is enough to know that an embedding is a vector representing a part of the text: a sentence, a word, or a part of a word, depending on the specific type of embedding used. This "part of a text" is called a token, and the process of splitting a text into tokens is called tokenization.]]></content><author><name>Javier Cancela</name><email>javier.cancela@hey.com</email></author><category term="AI" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[To understand how LLMs work, you have to understand embeddings. And to understand embeddings, you have to understand tokenizers.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New year, new blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/posts/new-year-new-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New year, new blog" /><published>2024-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/posts/new-year-new-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/posts/new-year-new-blog/"><![CDATA[ch
Ok, we are already in February, but I'm still trying to figure out my New Year's resolutions.

![Happy New Year!](https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1467810563316-b5476525c0f9?q=80&w=4738&auto=format&fit=crop&ixlib=rb-4.0.3&ixid=M3wxMjA3fDB8MHxwaG90by1wYWdlfHx8fGVufDB8fHx8fA%3D%3D)
*Happy New Year!*

# The setup

I'm keeping the blog in [GitHub Pages](https://pages.github.com/) and using a newer version of Jekyll with a [new theme]([Live Demo](https://sharadcodes.github.io/jekyll-theme-serial-programmer/)).

I'm trying Obsidian as the editing tool, as suggested in [this thread](https://x.com/kepano/status/1751355830103093375?s=20).

The site uses GA4 to collect basic analytics info. I didn't find any free alternative. Feel free to ping me if you know of one.

# The goal

Just to practice writing. It is a critical skill for an engineering manager and for any remote worker. Writing helps you to have more clarity, to think more carefully, and to communicate better.

It is also a good way to force me to learn: I pretend there are people reading me so I try to explain things in a way anybody can understand them. And that is one of the best ways I know to learn.

# The key

Consistency. As with some many things in life. We'll see.]]></content><author><name>Javier Cancela</name><email>javier.cancela@hey.com</email></author><category term="misc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[ch Ok, we are already in February, but I’m still trying to figure out my New Year’s resolutions.]]></summary></entry></feed>